Guide to the Hanover Royal Music Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- General Music and Books About Music, 1714-1951; Series I; 13.33; (615 boxes)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759
    - [Vocal music]. Vocal Works of Handel with a separate accompaniment arranged for the organ or piano-forte by Dr. John Clarke.... Score. Print (London: Button and Whitaker), 1808 (Box 59, Folder 290-292)
      Numbers 14, 17, 40-42
    - [Vocal music]. Scores. Print, undated (Box 512)
      Bound collection of excerpts from oratorios and operas
      Book-binder's title: Handel's Oratorio Songs
    - [Works]. Print (Leipzig: Händelgesellschaft), 1879, 1894 (Box 60, Folder 293-295)
      Lieferung LXXVIII: Partenope, 2 copies; Supplement: Concert III
    - [Works]. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel; Leipzig: Händelgesellschaft), 1860, 1868 (Box 513-516)
      Lieferung VIII: Theodora, 2 copies; Lieferung XXVII: Alcina, 2 copies
    - [Works]. Print (London: Button and Whitaker), [1809?] (Box 517-550)
      34 volumes, numbered on spine: 1, I, 2, 2, 3, 3, 4, 4, 5-30
      Book-binder's title: Handel's Works
  - Hart, Charles
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 551)
  - Hartley, Winchcombe, Mrs.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 60, Folder 296)
  - Hässler, Johann Wilhelm, 1747-1822
    - [Keyboard music]. Select Pieces for the Harpsichord or Piano-Forte...First Book.... Print (London: R. Wornum), undated (Box 61, Folder 297)
    - [Grande sonata, keyboard, 3 hands, op. 12]. A Grand Sonata, for three Hands on one Piano Forte or harpsichord.... Score. Print (London, R. Wornum), undated (Box 61, Folder 298)
      Initialed by the composer
  - Hauck, Wilhelm
    - Grosse Variationen über ein Thema aus Aschenbrödel. For keyboard. Print (no publisher), undated (Box 61, Folder 299)
  - Hauptmann, Moritz, 1792-1868
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 61-66, Folder 300-320)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 552)
  - Hawes, William, 1785-1846
    - No. 1, A Collection of Chants, Sanctuses & Responses.... Score. Print (London: W. Hawes), undated (Box 553)
    - Six Favorite Airs.... Score. Print (London: Birchall), 1810-1819?; (2 copies) (Box 67, Folder 321)
      Bound with: The Wreath of Love, The Spectre Knight, and Robin Adair
    - A Sett of Six Favorite Scotch Airs, Harmonized as Glees For three & four Voices.... Score. Print (London: for the author), undated; (2 copies) (Box 67, Folder 322)
      Cover labels: "Her Royal Highness Princess Elizabeth" and "Her Royal Highness Princess Mary"
    - Six Glees for Three and Four Voices, with an Accompaniment for the Piano-Forte.... Score. Print (London: Birchall), undated (Box 67, Folder 323)
  - Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809
    - [O Jesu, te invocamus]. Hymne...für vier Singstimmen und Orchester.... Score and parts (SATB). Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), undated (Box 67, Folder 324)
    - [Quartets, strings, H. III, 46, E-flat major. Andante]. In the third Quartetto of Haydn, for two Violins Tenor & Bass, op. 44. Arranged for keyboard. Manuscript, undated (Box 67, Folder 325)
      Appended: German Hymn's Harmonized by Julius Schläger, Hannr
    - [Quartets, strings]. Three Quartets...op. 65, set 1. Parts (2 vn, va, vc). Print (London: Bland), undated (Box 68, Folder 326)
      In D major, E-flat major, and C major
    - [Quartets, strings]. Trois Quatuors...op. 72, set 2. Parts (2 vn, va, vc). Print (London: Corri, Dussek & Co.), undated (Box 68, Folder 327)
      In C major, F major, and G minor
    - [Die Schöpfung]. La Création Oratorio, Arrangé En Harmonie.... Suites I and II. Parts (2 fl, 4 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, 2 tpt, trbn). Print (Paris: Pleyel), undated (Box 68-69, Folder 328-330)
    - [Die Schöpfung]. Die Schöpfung...Klavier Auszug.... Print, lithograph (Offenbach: André), undated (Box 69, Folder 331)
    - [Sonata]. Haydn's Celebrated Sonata, Op. 40, arranged for a full Military Band.... Parts (2 fl, 4 cl, 2 bn (1 part), spt, 2 hn, 2 tpt (1 part, trbn). Print (Dublin: J. B. Logier), undated (Box 69, Folder 332)
    - [Songs]. A Selection of Original Scots Songs in Three Parts.... Volumes 1-3. Score. Print (London: Napier), undated; Volume 2: 2 copies (Box 554-557)
      Volume 1 lacks title page
    - [Songs]. A Selection of Original Scots Songs in Three Parts.... Volume 3. Score. Print (London: Napier), undated; (2 copies) (Box 70, Folder 333-334)
    - [Symphonies]. No. [1, 2, 3] of Haydn's Grand Symphonies, Composed for Mr. Salomon's Concerts, and arranged for five Instruments...with an Accompaniment for the Piano Forte.... Parts (fl, 2 vn, va, vc, pf). Print (London: proprietor), undated (Box 71, Folder 335-336)
    - [Symphony]. Simphony of Haydn, No. 3. Part (spt). Manuscript, undated (Box 71, Folder 337)
    - [Symphonies]. No. [4, 5, 6] of Haydn's Grand Symphonies, Composed for Mr. Salomon's Concerts, and arranged for five Instruments...with an Accompaniment for the Piano Forte.... Parts (fl, 2 vn, va, vc, pf). Print (London: proprietor), undated (Box 71, Folder 338-339)
    - [Symphonies]. No. [7, 8, 9], Haydn's Grand Symphonies, Composed for Mr. Salomon's Concerts, and arranged for five Instruments...with an Accompaniment for the Piano Forte.... Parts (fl, 2 vn, va, vc, pf). Print (London: proprietor), circa 1800 (Box 72, Folder 340-341)
      Signed by John Peter Salomon
    - [Symphonies]. No. [10, 11, 12] of Haydn's Grand Symphonies, Composed for Mr. Salomon's Concerts, and arranged for five Instruments...with an Accompaniment for the Piano Forte.... Parts (fl, 2 vn, va, vc, pf). Print (London: for the proprietor Mr. Salomon), circa 1800 (Box 72, Folder 342-343)
    - [Symphonies]. Haydn's celebrated Symphonies...adapted for the Piano-forte, with an accompaniment for a violin & violoncello ad libitum...Nos 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12.... Parts (vn, vc, pf). Print (London: for Mr Salomon), undated (Box 558-559)
      On cover: H.R.H.P. Augusta
    - [Symphony]. Symphonie of Haydn, No. VII. Parts (2 tpt, trbn). Manuscript., undated (Box 73, Folder 344)
    - [Symphony, H. I, 94, G major. Andante]. Arranged for military band. Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 6 cl, 3 bn, spt, 3 hn, 3 tpt, 3 trn, timp). Manuscript, undated (Box 73, Folder 345)
    - [Symphony, H. I, 96, D major]. No.[6] of Haydn's Grand Symphonies, Composed for Mr. Salomon's Concerts, for a Full Band.... Parts (2 vn, va, b and vc (2 parts), fl, 2 ob, 2 bn (1 part), 2 hn, 2 tpt, timp). Print (London: for the proprietor), circa 1802 (Box 73, Folder 346)
    - [Symphony, H. I, 98, B-flat major]. No.[4] of Haydn's Grand Symphonies, Composed for Mr. Salomon's Concerts, for a Full Band.... Parts (2 vn, va, b and vc (2 parts), fl, 2 ob, 2 bn (1 part), 2 hn, 2 tpt, timp). Print (London: for the proprietor), circa 1802 (Box 73, Folder 347)
    - [Symphony, H. I, 99, E-flat major]. No. [10], Haydn's Grand Symphonies, Composed for Mr: Salomon's Concert, a full band.... Parts (2 vn, va, b and vc (2 parts), 2 fl, 2 ob, 2 cl, 2 bn (1 part), spt, 2 hn, 2 tpt, timp). Print (London: for the proprietor Mr. Salomon), circa 1802 (Box 73-74, Folder 348-349)
      Serpent part in manuscript
    - [Symphony, H. I, 101, D major]. No.[11] of Haydn's Grand Symphonies, Composed for Mr. Salomon's Concerts for a Full Band.... Parts (2 vn, va, vc and b (2 parts), fl, 2 ob, 2 cl, 2 bn (1 part), 2 hn, 2 tpt, timp). Print (London: for the proprietor), circa 1802 (Box 74, Folder 350)
      Manuscript cancels affixed to bassoon part
    - [Symphony, H. I, 102, B-flat major]. Haydns Grand Symphony, No.9, arranged for fifteen Instruments...by J. Collier.... Parts (2 fl, 6 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt, trbn). Print (London: W. Milhouse), undated (Box 74, Folder 351-352)
      E flat clarinet part missing pages 3-4
    - [Symphony, H. I, 103, E-flat major]. Arranged for military band by John Collier. Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 6 cl, 2 bn, spt, 3 hn, 3 tpt, 3 trbn, timp). Manuscript, undated (Box 75, Folder 353-355)
    - [Symphonies]. Parts (2nd vn, va, b, b obligato, fl, 2 ob, 2 bn (1 part), 2 hn). Print, 1796-1799, undated (Box 75-78, Folder 356-367)
      Bound collection: [Symphony, H. I, 100, G major]. Grande Sinfonie militaire.... First edition. (Offenbach: André, [1799]); [Symphony, H. I, 97, C major]. First edition. (André, [1796]); symphonies of Ignaz Pleyel; works of other composers
      With additional parts for Haydn Symphonies 97 and 100, and other works, manuscript and print
      Extensive manuscript annotations; some parts in manuscript; some manuscript parts on paper watermarked 1803
    - [Trio, piano, strings, H. XV, 14, A-flat major]. A Favorite Sonata for the Piano Forte or Harpsichord with Accompaniments for a violin and violoncello...Op.68.... Part (kbd). Print (London: Longman and Broderip), undated (Box 78, Folder 368)
    - [Trios, piano, strings]. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), undated (Box 79, Folder 369-371)
    - [Violin and piano music]. The Quintessence of Haydn consisting of five sonatas and a duet for the Piano Forte or Harpsichord with an Accompaniment for a Violin.... Part (kbd). Print (London: Longman & Broderip), undated (Box 79, Folder 372)
  - Hecker, Adolph
    - Music. Manuscript, 1862 (Box 80, Folder 373)
  - Heidrich, Heinrich
    - Music. Print, 1843 (Box 560)
  - Heidrich
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 80, Folder 374-375)
  - Heije, J. P. (Jan Pieter), 1809-1876
    - Music. Print, typeset, undated (Box 561)
  - Heimberg, Ernst
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 80, Folder 376)
  - Heine, C. Ludwig
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 81, Folder 377-380)
  - Heinemann, Carl
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 562)
  - Heinroth, Johann August Günther, 1780-1846
    - Music. Print, 1837? (Box 82, Folder 381)
  - Hellmesberger, Georg, 1800-1873
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 563)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 82, Folder 382)
  - Herbert, George B.
    - Three Rounds, With an Accompaniment for the Piano Forte.... Books 1-2. Score. Print (London: Goulding), 1825? (Box 564)
      Book-binder's label: Charles Murton, 50 Long Acre
  - Herfurth, L.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 82, Folder 383)
  - Hertel, Peter Ludwig, 1817-1899
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 82, Folder 384)
  - Herrmann, Gottfried, 1808-1878
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 565)
  - Heyssig, Alfred
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 566)
  - Himmel, Friedrich Heinrich, 1765-1814
    - Der bescheidene Liebhaber.... Song. Score. Print (no publisher), undated (Box 82, Folder 385)
    - [Canzonets]. Six Canzonets with a Piano Forte Accompaniment.... Score. Print (London: Clementi, Banger, Hyde, Collard & Davis), undated (Box 82, Folder 386)
    - [Gesänge aus Tiedges Urania, op.18]. Score. Print, typeset. (Oranienburg: Bureau de Musique), 1804 (Box 567)
      Dedication to Queen Sophie Charlotte
    - [Psalm 146]. Der 146te. Score. Manuscript, undated (Box 82, Folder 387)
    - Seelen Wanderung der Blumen. Score. Manuscript, undated (Box 82, Folder 388)
    - Trauer-Cantate zur Begraebnissfeyer Seiner Königlichen Majestät von Preussen Friedrich Wilhelm II.... Score. Print, typeset (Hamburg: in der Meynschen Notendruckerei), 1798? (Box 83, Folder 389)
    - Vater Unser von Mahlmann und Himmel. Score. Manuscript, circa 1809 (Box 568-569)
    - Vater Unser von Mahlmann und Himmel. Parts (SSTTB (solo), SSTTBB (chorus), 2 fl, 2 ob, 2 cl, 2 bn, 2 hn, 2 tpt, timp, 2 vn, va, b). Manuscript, circa 1809 (Box 83-85, Folder 390-398)
    - Was ist heilig? Score. Print, typeset (no publisher), undated (Box 86, Folder 399)
  - Hodges, Mrs. (Ann Mary), d. 1797
    - Songs composed by Mrs Hodges, harmonized and published by Mr. Hüllmandel.... Score. Print (no publisher), 1798 (Box 86, Folder 400)
      Dedication to the Queen
  - Hodges, George Lloyd
    - A Collection of Peninsular Melodies.... No. 1-2. Score. Print (London: Goulding, D'Almaine), 1830? (Box 86-87, Folder 401-402)
  - Holder, J. W. (Joseph William), 1764-1832
    - The Royal Visit to Bath: A Divertimento, for the Piano Forte.... Print (London: Goulding, D'Almaine Potter), undated (Box 87, Folder 403)
  - Hollis, G. W. A.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 87, Folder 404)
  - Holzapfel
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 87, Folder 405)
  - Holzapfel, J. S. G.
    - Neuer Liederkranz...Erstes Heft.... Score. Print, typeset (Lemgo: in Commission der Meyerschen Hofbuchhandlung), undated (Box 87, Folder 406)
  - Holzmiller, Eduard
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 87, Folder 407)
  - Honauer, Leontzi, ca. 1730-ca. 1790
    - [Quartets, keyboard, strings, horns, op. 4]. IV Quatuor pour le clavecin avec accompagnement de deux violons et basse et deux cors ad libitum.... Part (kbd). Print (Paris: author), undated (Box 87, Folder 408)
  - Horecki, Feliks, 1796-1870
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 87, Folder 409)
  - Horn, Charles Edward, 1786-1849
    - Faithful Ellen.... Score. Print (Lonson: Welsh), undated (Box 88, Folder 410)
    - Oberon's court.... Score. Print (London: Royal Harmonic Institution), 1831 (Box 570)
    - [Peveril of the Peak. Excerpts]. Score. Print (London: Welsh & Hawes), circa 1826-1828 (Box 571)
      Binding: monogram of Princess Augusta
  - Horn, Charles Frederick, 1762-1830
    See also: Music Collections/Manuscript Music Books/Amelia, Princess, daughter of George III, King of Great Britain, 1783-1810
    See also: Music Collections/Manuscript Music Books/Augusta Sophia, Princess, daughter of George III, King of Great Britain, 1768-1840
    - [Divertimentos]. A Collection of Divertimentos for the Piano Forte With an Accompagnement for a Violin.... Parts (pf, vn). Print (London: author), undated; Piano part: 2 copies (Box 88, Folder 411)
      Violin part incomplete
    - [Fugues]. A Sett of 12 Fugues Composed for the Organ by Sebastian Bach arranged as Quartettos.... Part (basso continuo). Print (London: author), 1807 (Box 572)
    - [Fugues]. A Sett of 12 Fugues Composed for the Organ by Sebastian Bach arranged as Quartettos.... Parts (2 vn). Print (London: author), 1807 (Box 88, Folder 412)
    - Hark the Loud Trumpet.... Score. Print (London: author), undated (Box 88, Folder 413)
    - [Minuet]. Tempo di Menuetto, con Trio. For 2 clarinets, 2 horns, bassoon, and serpent. Score. Holograph, 1809 (Box 88, Folder 414)
      Annotation, possibly by Princess Augusta: Her Royal Highness the Princess Augusta's Minuet, composed by Horn & Carnaby, 1809
    - Prelude & Rondo for the Piano Forte.... Print (London: C. Mitchell), undated (Box 88, Folder 415)
      Intialed by the composer?
    - [Sonatas, keyboard, violin, violoncello, op. 1]. Six Sonatas for the Piano Forte, or Harpsichord with an Accompagnement for a violin & violoncello.... Parts (kbd, vn, vc). Print (London: author), undated (Box 88, Folder 416-417)
    - [Sonatas, keyboard, violin, violoncello, op. 1]. Six Sonatas for the PianoForte, or Harpsichord with an Accompanyment for a violin & violoncello.... Part (kbd). Print (London: author), 1786 (Box 89, Folder 418)
      Manuscript annotation: Princess Amelia
      Other manuscript annotations
    - [Sonatas]. Parts (vn). Print (London: author), undated (Box 573)
      Bound collection: [Sonatas, keyboard, violin, violoncello, op. 1]. Six Sonatas for the Piano Forte or Harpsichord with an Accompagnement for a violin & violoncello....; [Sonatas, keyboard, violin or flute, op. 11]. Three Sonatas for the Piano Forte or Harpsichord with an accompaniment for a violin or flute...
    - [Sonatas, piano, flute, oboe, or violin, op. 3]. Three Sonatas for the Grand & Small Pianoforte with an accompaniment for the vlute, oboe, or violin.... Parts (pf, fl/ob/vn). Print (London: Longman and Broderip), undated (Box 89, Folder 419)
    - Trafalgar: an Heroic Song.... Score. Print (London: Goulding, Phipps, D'Almaine & Co.), 1805; (4 copies) (Box 89, Folder 420)
    - [Unidentified]. Holograph sketches, undated (Box 89, Folder 421)
      On outer pages of a manuscript in an unidentified hand, titled "Minuets For Her Majesty's Birth Day 1790"
  - Horsley, William, 1774-1858
    - A Fourth Collection of Glees, Canons.... Score. Print (London: for the author, by Birchall, Lonsdale and Mills), 1827 (Box 574)
  - Hübner, Caroline
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 89, Folder 422)
  - Hughes, Joseph T.
    - British Melodies, the Composition of Master Hughes, from the fourth to the ninth year of his age.... For harp. Print (London: for the proprietor, by D'Almaine), undated; (2 copies) (Box 89-90, Folder 423-424)
    - The Celebrated Welch Air...to which is added The Juvenile Bards Idea...by Master Hughes.... For harp. Print (London: Welsh), undated (Box 90, Folder 425)
    - The Infant Farewell. Manuscript, undated (Box 90, Folder 426)
  - Hüllmandel, Nicolas-Joseph, 1756-1823
    - [Sonatas, keyboard, violin, 1773/4]. Six Sonates de Clavecin ou Forte Piano Avec accompagnement de Violon ad Libitum...Oeuvre Ier..... Parts (kbd, vn). Print (Paris: Saunier), undated (Box 90, Folder 427)
    - [Sonatas, keyboard, violin, 1782]. Trois Sonates pour le piano forte ou le clavecin...avec accompagnement d'un Violon...Oeuvre VI.e.... Parts (kbd, vn). Print (Paris: Saumier), undated (Box 90, Folder 428)
  - Hummel, Johann Nepomuk, 1778-1837
    - [The Orphan's Ode to the Patriots]. New National Music: The Orphan's Ode to the Patriots, A Cantata...arranged...by...the Lady of Dunstaffnage.... Parts (pf and voice (1 part), hp), Print (no publisher), circa 1833; (5 copies) (Box 90-91, Folder 429-431)
      Dedication to Princess Victoria
      One copy arranged by the Lady of the Isles
    - [Sonatas, keyboard, violin/flute, violoncello]. Three Sonatas for the Piano-Forte or Harpsichord with Accompaniments for a violin or flute, & violoncello...Op.III.... Parts (kbd, vn or fl (1 part), vc). Print (London: author), undated (Box 91, Folder 432)
    - [Variations, piano, op. 1]. Three Sets of Variations for the Piano Forte or Harp.... Print (London: for the author), 1791 (Box 91, Folder 433)
  - Jaell, Alfred, 1832-1882
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 575)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 884)
  - Jahn, Otto, 1813-1869
    - W. A. Mozart. Volumes 1-4. Biography. Print (Leipzig; Breitkopf & Härtel), 1856-1859 (Box 576-579)
      Inscribed: Arnold Wehner
  - Jähns, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1809-1888
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 580-581)
  - Jansen, F. Gustav, 1831-1910
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 91, Folder 434)
  - Johnson, James, ca. 1750-1811
    - The Scots Musical Museum.... Volumes 1-4. Songs. Print (Edinburgh: Johnson), 1787-1792 (Box 582)
  - Jommelli, Nicolò, 1714-1774
    - The Periodical Overture In eight parts.... Parts (2 ob (1 part), 2 hn, 2 vn, va, b). Print (London: Preston & Son), undated (Box 91, Folder 435)
    - [Requiem, E-flat major]. Requiem.... Score and parts (SATB). Print (Hamburg: Cranz), undated (Box 92, Folder 436)
  - Jones, Edward, 1752-1824
    - Cambro-British Melodies...By the late Edward Jones.... Volume 3, part 2. For keyboard. Print (London: Rees), 1825? (Box 92, Folder 437)
    - A Selection of the most admired and original German waltzes.... For harp or piano. Print (London: author), 1806 (Box 583)
      Includes hand-colored engraving by Thomas Rowlandson
  - Jones, John, 1728-1796
    - Sixty Single and Double Chants. Manuscript, 1785 (Box 584)
  - Jones, William, 1726-1800
    - A Treatise on the Art of Music.... Second edition. Print (Sudbury: Fulcher; London: Longman), 1827 (Box 585)
  - Jouve, J.
    - [Forest of Hermanstadt. Overture]. The Overture to the Forest of Hermanstadt, A Melo Drama.... For keyboard. Print (London: Clementi, Banger, Hyde, Collard, & Davis), undated (Box 92, Folder 438)
      With: The Forest of Hermanstadt, A Melo Drama. Title page only. Print (London: Clementi, Banger, Hyde, Collard, & Davis, undated)
  - Kaufmann, J. L. W.
    - Music. Manuscript, 1857 (Box 92, Folder 439)
  - Kaufmann, Wilhelm
    - Music. Manuscript, 1856 (Box 92, Folder 440)
  - Kéler, Béla, 1820-1882
    - Music. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 586)
  - Kelly, Michael, 1762-1826
    - [Blue Beard. Excerpts]. The Overture and Music of the Grand Dramatic Romance of Blue Beard.... Score. Print (London: Chappell), undated (Box 92, Folder 441)
    - [Of age to-morrow. Excerpts]. The Overture and Music in the Musical Entertainment Of Age To-Morrow.... Score. Print (London: for the author by Corri, Dussek & Co.), undated (Box 587)
      Composer's stamp
    - [Of age to-morrow. Excerpts]. The Overture and Music in the Musical Entertainment Of Age To-Morrow.... Score. Print (London: for the author by Corri, Dussek & Co.). Unbound, undated (Box 92, Folder 442)
    - Six Pieces From the Favorite Operas, of Il Ratto di Proserpina and Il Trionfo dell Amor Fraterno, composed by Winter.... Arrangement of music by Peter von Winter for military band. Parts (2 fl, 3 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, 2 tpt (1 part)). Print (London: M. Kelly), undated (Box 93, Folder 443-444)
      With partial manuscript transcription of first bassoon part
  - Kemp, Joseph, 1778-1824
    - Allons au Brasil, Impromptu Pour le Piano Forte.... Print (London: author), before 1824 (Box 93, Folder 445)
      Manuscript annotations, possibly by the composer
    - By Dimpled Brook and Fountain Brim: A Trio (From a Song in Comus) Harmonized by Joseph Kemp.... For voices and piano. Score. Print (London: for and by J. Kemp, 1802? (Box 93, Folder 446)
    - War Anthem. Score. Holograph, 1803 (Box 93, Folder 447)
  - Kern, Carl August, 1836-1897
    - Music. Print, typeset, 1913 (Box 93, Folder 448)
  - Kerr, Louisa Hay
    - The Coronal, a collection of Songs.... Score. Print (London: Willis, etc.), undated (Box 588)
    - Melodies.... Score. Print (London: Novello), 1834? (Box 589)
    - Songs of Hope and Memory.... Score. Print (London: Mills), undated (Box 590)
      Dedication to Queen Victoria
  - Király, Joseph Paul von
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 591)
  - Kjerulf, Halfdan, 1815-1868
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 93, Folder 449)
  - Klein, Bernhard, 1793-1832
    - Hymne, Gedicht von L. Rellstab für eine Singstimme mit Begleitung des Pianoforte.... Score. Print (Elberfeld: Betzhold), undated (Box 94, Folder 450)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 94, Folder 451-452)
  - Kletzer, Feri
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 592)
  - Kloss, Carl
    - Music. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 593-594)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 94, Folder 453)
  - Klussmann
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 94, Folder 454)
  - Knyvett, Charles, 1773-1852
    - Six Airs Harmonized for Three or Four Voices.... Score. Print (London: Chappell), undated; (2 copies) (Box 95, Folder 455)
  - Koch, Eduard Emil, 1809-1871
    - Geschichte des Kirchenlieds und Kirchengesangs der christlichen, insbesondere der deutschen evangelischen Kirche. Volumes 1-4. Print (Stuttgart: C. Belser), 1852-1853 (Box 595-598)
  - Köchy, Carl
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 885)
  - Kollmann, Augustus Frederic Christopher, 1756-1829
    - [Divertimento, piano, 6 hands]. A Divertimento for Three Performers on One Piano-Forte.... Score. Print (London: author), [1799] (Box 95, Folder 456)
    - [Geistliche Lieder]. Sechs geistliche Lieder.... Score. Print (Leipzig: J. G. I. Breitkopf), [circa 1784] (Box 599)
    - An Essay on Practical Musical Composition.... Print (London: author), 1799 (Box 600)
      Signed by the author
    - An Introduction to the Art of Preluding and Extemporizing in Six Lessons for the Harpsichord or Harp...Opr. 3d.... Print (London: R. Wornum), [1792] (Box 95, Folder 457)
  - Könemann, F. von
    - Music. Manuscript, 1839 (Box 601)
  - König, Carl
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 602)
  - König, Josef Eduard
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 95, Folder 458)
    - Music. Manuscript and print, 1867? (Box 603)
      Laid in: autograph letter signed, from the composer to Ernst August (1845-1923), as Crown Prince of Hanover
  - Kopetzky, Wendelin
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 604)
  - Körner, Gotthilf Wilhelm